# TEJAS GOKHALE

♥ 699 S Mill Ave, Tempe AZ ■ tgokhale@asu.edu ♥ tejasgokhale.com **G** Google Scholar

### RESEARCH INTERESTS

I work on computer vision, machine learning, and natural language processing - very often at their wonderful intersection. My focus is "semantic vision", i.e. building systems that assign meaning to scenes captured by cameras. My domain expertise lies in devising adversarial machine learning algorithms for tackling situations such as domain shift, semantic shift, signal corruptions, etc. as well as learning to discover useful data transformations that can improve the diversity of training data. I am also interested in developing frameworks for benchmarking and analyzing the robustness, reliability, and generalizability of semantic vision systems.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Doctor of Philosophy, Arizona State University

2018-present

School of Computing and Augmented Intelligence

Advisors: Yezhou Yang, Chitta Baral

## Master of Science, Carnegie Mellon University

2017

Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering

Advisor: Aswin C. Sankaranarayanan

## Bachelor of Engineering (Honours), Birla Institute of Technology and Science

2015

Department of Electrical and Electronics Engineering

## **PUBLICATIONS**

My work has been published at several premier AI venues such as AAAI (h5-index: 180); computer vision conferences: ICCV (h5-index: 239), ECCV (h5-index: 186), WACV (h5-index: 76); natural language processing conferences: ACL (h5-index: 169), EMNLP (h5-index: 154), NAACL (h5-index: 105).

## O Conference Proceedings

(5 ACL, 2 AAAI, 2 EMNLP, 1 ECCV, 1 ICCV, 1 NAACL, 1 WACV)

- [C1] Improving Diversity with Adversarially Learned Transformations for Domain Generalization T. Gokhale, R. Anirudh, J. Thiagarajan, B. Kailkhura, C. Baral, Y. Yang https://arxiv.org/abs/2206.07736 to appear in WACV 2023
- [C2] CRIPP-VQA: Counterfactual Reasoning about Implicit Physical Properties via Video Question Answering M. Patel, T. Gokhale, C. Baral, Y. Yang to appear in EMNLP 2022
- [C3] Semantically Distributed Robust Optimization for Vision-and-Language Inference T. Gokhale, A. Chaudhary, P. Banerjee, C. Baral, Y. Yang https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.07165 ACL Findings 2022
- [C4] Generalized but not Robust? Comparing the Effects of Data Modification Methods on Out-of-Domain Generalization and Adversarial Robustness
  - T. Gokhale, S. Mishra, M. Luo, B. Sachdeva, C. Baral https://arxiv.org/abs/2203.07653

ACL Findings 2022

[C5] Unsupervised Natural Language Inference Using PHL Triplet Generation N. Varshney, P. Banerjee, T. Gokhale, C. Baral https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.08438 ACL Findings 2022 [C6] To Find Waldo You Need Contextual Cues: Debiasing Who's Waldo Y. Luo, P. Banerjee, T. Gokhale, Y. Yang, C. Baral https://arxiv.org/abs/2203.16682 ACL 2022 [C7] Improving Biomedical Information Retrieval with Neural Retrievers M. Luo, A. Mitra, T. Gokhale, C. Baral https://arxiv.org/abs/2201.07745 **AAAI 2022** [C8] Weakly Supervised Relative Spatial Reasoning for Visual Question Answering P. Banerjee, T. Gokhale, Y. Yang, C. Baral https://arxiv.org/abs/2109.01934 ICCV 2021 [C9] WeaQA: Weak Supervision via Captions for Visual Question Answering P. Banerjee, T. Gokhale, Y. Yang, C. Baral https://arxiv.org/abs/2012.02356 ACL Findings 2021 [C10] Self-Supervised Test-Time Learning for Reading Comprehension P. Banerjee, T. Gokhale, C. Baral https://arxiv.org/abs/2103.11263 NAACL 2021 [C11] Attribute-Guided Adversarial Training for Robustness to Natural Perturbations T. Gokhale, R. Anirudh, B. Kailkhura, J. Thiagarajan, C. Baral, Y. Yang https://arxiv.org/abs/2012.01806 **AAAI 2021** [C12] Mutant: A Training Paradigm for Out-of-Distribution Generalization in Visual Question Answering T. Gokhale, P. Banerjee, C. Baral, Y. Yang https://arxiv.org/abs/2009.08566 **EMNLP 2021** [C13] Video2commonsense: Generating commonsense descriptions to enrich video captioning Z. Fang\*, T. Gokhale\*, P. Banerjee, C. Baral, Y. Yang **EMNLP 2021** https://arxiv.org/abs/2003.05162 [C14] VQA-LOL: Visual question answering under the lens of logic T. Gokhale, P. Banerjee, C. Baral, Y. Yang https://arxiv.org/abs/2002.08325 ECCV 2020 Workshop Proceedings (2 CVPR) [W1] Halluci-Net: Scene Completion by Exploiting Object Co-occurrence Relationships K. Kulkarni, T. Gokhale, R. Singh, P. Turaga, A. Sankaranarayanan Al for Content Creation @ CVPR 2021 https://arxiv.org/abs/2004.08614 [W2] Cooking With Blocks: A Recipe for Visual Reasoning on Image-Pairs T. Gokhale, S. Sampat, Z. Fang, Y. Yang, C. Baral Long version: https://arxiv.org/abs/1905.12042 Vision Meets Cognition @ CVPR'19

O Preprints

[P1] Poisoning of Image Classifiers via Selective Batch SamplingE. Wisdom, T. Gokhale, Y. Yang

in review

[P2] Domain Interpolation Sensitivity for Characterizing Distribution Shift J. Feinglass, T. Gokhale, C. Baral, Y. Yang

in review

# Book Manuscript

[B1] Advances in Multi-Modal Information Retrieval
(In Preparation) for Springer N

for Springer Nature Synthesis Lectures on Computer Vision

# O Grant Writing

I am actively involved in conceptualizing and writing grant proposals with my advisors. This proposed work builds upon contributions made by my PhD thesis.

[1] Decentralized Authorship Attribution

PI: Chitta Baral

Submitted to IARPA, 2022

[2] An Active Approach for Data Engineering to Improve Vision-Language Tasks

PI: Yezhou Yang, Co-PI: Chitta Baral

Funded by NSF, 2021

Summer 2021

Summer 2020

#### RESEARCH EMPLOYMENT

Microsoft Research Summer 2022

Research Intern, Adaptive Systems and Interaction Group

Mentors: Hamid Palangi (+Besa Nushi, Vibhav Vineet, Eric Horvitz)

Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory Research Scholar, Machine Intelligence Group

Mentor: Rushil Anirudh (+Jay Thiagarajan, Bhavya Kailkhura)

Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory

Research Scholar, Machine Intelligence Group

Mentor: Rushil Anirudh (+Jay Thiagarajan, Bhavya Kailkhura)

Snapchat Research Summer 2018

Research Intern, Computational Imaging Group

Mentor: Guru Krishnan & Shree Nayar

Carnegie Mellon University 2017–2018

Graduate Student Researcher, ECE Department

Advisor: Aswin Sankaranarayanan

#### **INVITED TALKS**

Oct'22, (Invited Talk) "Robust Semantic Vision"

University of Illinois at Chicago

Oct'22, (Invited Talk) "Benchmarking Spatial Relationships in Text-to-Image Generation" Microsoft Research

Mar'22, (Guest Lecture) "Introduction to Generalization in Semantic Vision"

ASU CSE 598

Sep'21, (Invited) "Robust Visual Understanding",

ASU ML Club

Aug'19, "Vision Beyond Pixels", IJCAI Doctoral Consortium,

IJCAI 2019, Macao Telluride 2019

Jul'19, "Reasoning about Objects and Actions via Block-Play",

ciluitae 201.

Apr'18, (Invited) "Deep Learning Methods in Imaging and Computer Vision",

BITS Goa

# **TEACHING**

Teaching Assistant, Arizona State University CSE310: Data Structures & Algorithms CSE408: Multimedia Information Systems, CSE110: Introduction to Programming,	Spring 2020, ASU Spring 2019, ASU Fall 2018, ASU
Guest Lecturer, Arizona State University CSE598, Perception in Robotics CSE408, Multimedia Information Systems	Spring 2022 Spring 2019, ASU
Course Development  CSE591: Frontier Topics in Vision & Language [YouTube] [website] Spring 2021  I was part of the team that designed this class as a series of (weekly) invited seminars, followed by paper reading, discussion, and brainstorming in the classroom.	
Student Instructor, CTE: Advanced Image Processing,	Spring 2015, BITS Pilani
MENTORING	
PhD Students Ethan Wisdom (see publication [P1])	Ph.D. CS [current]
MS (Thesis) Students Maitreya Patel (see publication [C2]) Huiliang Shao, Abhishek Chaudhary (see publication [C3])	M.S. CS [current] M.S. CE 2022 [current] M.S. CS 2021 [thesis]
Capstone Mentor, mentored five B.S. CS students in projects on vision & language	AY 2019-20
Project Mentor, CSE598 - Perception in Robotics, ASU	Spring 2022
Project Mentor, CSE576 - Natural Language Processing, ASU	Fall 2018
SERVICE / LEADERSHIP	
Program Committee / Conference Reviewer	
NeurIPS: Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems ICLR: International Conference on Learning Representations AAAI: AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence ECCV: European Conference on Computer Vision EMNLP: Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing ACL: Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics NAACL: North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics WACV: IEEE Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision ICRA: International Conference on Robotics and Automation IROS: IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems	2022 2022 2021–2023 2022 2021–2022 2021–2022 2021–2022 2021–2023 2019–2023 2022
Journal Reviewer  RA-L: IEEE Robotics and Automation Letter  MVAP: Springer Machine Vision and Applications	2020 2020
Workshop Organizer ODRUM: Workshop on Open-Domain Retrieval under Multi-Modal Settings,	CVPR 2022 [Website] [YouTube]

Organizer, 2021 Frontiers of V&L Seminar Series, [Website], [YouTube] ASU Founder, Summer Vision Reading Group, [Website], multi-university initiative

Volunteer, 2019 Southwest Robotics Symposium,Tempe AZVolunteer, International Conference on Machine Learning 2020,VirtualAdvisor, ASU Machine Learning Club,ASUAward Reviewer, GPSA Teaching Award ReviewerASUMentor, Graduate Student Mentorship Program,ASUStudent Mentor, Peer Mentorship ProgramBITS Pilani

## AWARDS AND RECOGNITION

NeurIPS Top Reviewer NeurIPS 2022 CVPR 2022 Doctoral Consortium **CVPR 2022** ICLR Best Reviewer ICLR 2022 SCAI Doctoral Fellowship (ASU), 2020-2022 Engineering Graduate Fellowship, (ASU Engineering), 2020 Graduate College Travel Award, (ASU), for CVPR 2022, ICCV 2021, EMNLP 2020, ECCV 2020 IJCAI 2019 Doctoral Consortium, IJCAI 2019 Inducted, IEEE Eta Kappa Nu, Sigma Chapter (CMU), Jan 2017 National Talent Scholarship (Govt. of India), 2007-2015

## **REFERENCES**

Yezhou Yang Associate Professor Arizona State University yz.yang@asu.edu
Chitta Baral Professor Arizona State University chitta@asu.edu
Heni Ben Amor Associate Professor Arizona State University hbenamor@asu.edu
Rushil Anirudh Research Scientist Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory anirudh1@llnl.gov